[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "questionText": "What is the capital of UK?",
    "answers": ["London", "Paris", "New York", "Berlin"],
    "correctAnswer": "London",
    "category": "Geography"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "questionText": "When is Saint George's Day celebrated?",
    "answers": ["23rd April", "1st May", "17th March", "30th November"],
    "correctAnswer": "23rd April",
    "category": "History and Culture"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "questionText": "Who is the patron saint of Scotland?",
    "answers": ["Saint Andrew", "Saint George", "Saint David", "Saint Patrick"],
    "correctAnswer": "Saint Andrew",
    "category": "History and Culture"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "questionText": "What is the UK's form of government?",
    "answers": [
      "Constitutional Monarchy",
      "Absolute Monarchy",
      "Republic",
      "Dictatorship"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Constitutional Monarchy",
    "category": "Government and Politics"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "questionText": "Which famous document, signed in 1215, is known as the foundation of constitutional law?",
    "answers": [
      "Magna Carta",
      "Declaration of Independence",
      "Treaty of Versailles",
      "Bill of Rights"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Magna Carta",
    "category": "History and Culture"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "questionText": "Who is the current monarch of the UK as of May 2023?",
    "answers": [
      "Queen Elizabeth II",
      "King Charles III",
      "King William V",
      "Queen Victoria"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "King Charles III",
    "category": "History and Culture"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "questionText": "What is the official language of the UK?",
    "answers": ["English", "Spanish", "German", "French"],
    "correctAnswer": "English",
    "category": "History and Culture"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "questionText": "Which monarch has been on the throne the longest in the UK?",
    "answers": [
      "Queen Elizabeth II",
      "Queen Victoria",
      "King George III",
      "King Henry VIII"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Queen Elizabeth II",
    "category": "History and Culture"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "questionText": "In what year did The Bill of Rights come into effect?",
    "answers": ["1589", "1689", "1789", "1889"],
    "correctAnswer": "1689",
    "category": "History and Culture"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "questionText": "What is the currency used in the UK?",
    "answers": ["Pound Sterling", "Euro", "Dollar", "Yen"],
    "correctAnswer": "Pound Sterling",
    "category": "Government and Politics"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "questionText": "What is the national flower of the UK?",
    "answers": ["Rose", "Lily", "Daisy", "Tulip"],
    "correctAnswer": "Rose",
    "category": "Symbols and Monuments"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "questionText": "What is the name of the famous bell in the clock tower of the Palace of Westminster?",
    "answers": ["Big Ben", "Little Ben", "Westminster Bell", "Palace Bell"],
    "correctAnswer": "Big Ben",
    "category": "Symbols and Monuments"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "questionText": "What is the name of the river that flows through London?",
    "answers": ["Thames", "Seine", "Danube", "Rhine"],
    "correctAnswer": "Thames",
    "category": "Geography"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "questionText": "What is the name of the UK's national anthem?",
    "answers": [
      "God Save the Queen",
      "Rule Britannia",
      "Land of Hope and Glory",
      "Jerusalem"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "God Save the Queen",
    "category": "History and Culture"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "questionText": "Who is the patron saint of Scotland?",
    "answers": ["St. Andrew", "St. George", "St. David", "St. Patrick"],
    "correctAnswer": "St. Andrew",
    "category": "History and Culture"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "questionText": "Who is the patron saint of Wales?",
    "answers": ["St. David", "St. George", "St. Andrew", "St. Patrick"],
    "correctAnswer": "St. David",
    "category": "History and Culture"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "questionText": "What is the name of the UK's flag?",
    "answers": ["Union Jack", "Stars and Stripes", "Tricolour", "Maple Leaf"],
    "correctAnswer": "Union Jack",
    "category": "Symbols and Monuments"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "questionText": "What is the name of the famous university in Cambridge?",
    "answers": [
      "Cambridge University",
      "Oxford University",
      "Harvard University",
      "Yale University"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Cambridge University",
    "category": "Geography"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "questionText": "What is the name of the famous university in Oxford?",
    "answers": [
      "Oxford University",
      "Cambridge University",
      "Harvard University",
      "Yale University"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Oxford University",
    "category": "Geography"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "questionText": "What is the name of the famous palace in London?",
    "answers": [
      "Buckingham Palace",
      "Kensington Palace",
      "Windsor Castle",
      "Hampton Court Palace"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Buckingham Palace",
    "category": "Symbols and Monuments"
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "questionText": "What is the name of the UK's national animal?",
    "answers": ["Unicorn", "Lion", "Horse", "Dragon"],
    "correctAnswer": "Unicorn",
    "category": "Symbols and Monuments"
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "questionText": "Who wrote the famous novel 'Pride and Prejudice'?",
    "answers": [
      "Jane Austen",
      "Emily Bronte",
      "Charlotte Bronte",
      "Virginia Woolf"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Jane Austen",
    "category": "History and Culture"
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "questionText": "What is the name of the famous London Eye?",
    "answers": [
      "Millennium Wheel",
      "Giant Ferris Wheel",
      "Tower Wheel",
      "Roundabout Wheel"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Millennium Wheel",
    "category": "Geography"
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "questionText": "What is the name of the famous river that runs through Edinburgh?",
    "answers": ["Water of Leith", "River Clyde", "River Tay", "River Dee"],
    "correctAnswer": "Water of Leith",
    "category": "Geography"
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "questionText": "What is the name of the famous prehistoric monument in Wiltshire?",
    "answers": [
      "Stonehenge",
      "Avebury",
      "Silbury Hill",
      "West Kennet Long Barrow"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Stonehenge",
    "category": "Symbols and Monuments"
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "questionText": "What is the name of the famous art museum in London?",
    "answers": [
      "Tate Modern",
      "National Gallery",
      "British Museum",
      "Victoria and Albert Museum"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "National Gallery",
    "category": "Geography"
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "questionText": "What is the name of the famous war memorial in London?",
    "answers": [
      "Cenotaph",
      "Tower of London",
      "Westminster Abbey",
      "St. Paul's Cathedral"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Cenotaph",
    "category": "Symbols and Monuments"
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "questionText": "What is the name of the famous festival held in Edinburgh every summer?",
    "answers": [
      "Edinburgh Festival Fringe",
      "Glastonbury Festival",
      "Reading Festival",
      "Leeds Festival"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Edinburgh Festival Fringe",
    "category": "History and Culture"
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "questionText": "What is the name of the famous lake in the Lake District National Park?",
    "answers": ["Windermere", "Ullswater", "Derwentwater", "Coniston Water"],
    "correctAnswer": "Windermere",
    "category": "Geography"
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "questionText": "MPs are elected at a General Election which is held:",
    "answers": [
      "every 3 years",
      "every 4 years",
      "every 5 years",
      "every 6 years"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "every 5 years",
    "category": "Government and Politics"
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "questionText": "MPs can only be contacted by telephone. Is this true or false?",
    "answers": ["True", "False"],
    "correctAnswer": "False",
    "category": "Government and Politics"
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "questionText": "1918 was an important date in the history of womenâ€™s rights because:",
    "answers": [
      "Women earned the right to equal pay at work.",
      "Women were allowed to buy property.",
      "Women were allowed to drive a car.",
      "Women were given the right to vote."
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Women were given the right to vote.",
    "category": "History and Culture"
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "questionText": "A 'bank holiday' is a public holiday when only banks close for the day. Is this true or false?",
    "answers": ["True", "False"],
    "correctAnswer": "False",
    "category": "Government and Politics"
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "questionText": "A 'council' is a group of people who are elected to govern an area. Is this true or false?",
    "answers": ["True", "False"],
    "correctAnswer": "True",
    "category": "Government and Politics"
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "questionText": "One of the aims of the United Nations is to:",
    "answers": [
      "Promote free trade.",
      "Ensure people learn English.",
      "Protect Wildlife across the EU.",
      "Promote international peace and security."
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Promote international peace and security.",
    "category": "Government and Politics"
  },
  {
    "id": 36,
    "questionText": "The Channel Islands and the Isle of Man are part of the UK. Is this true or false?",
    "answers": ["True", "False"],
    "correctAnswer": "False",
    "category": "Geography"
  },
  {
    "id": 37,
    "questionText": "'Great Britain' refers to:",
    "answers": [
      "England and Scotland",
      "England and Wales",
      "England, Wales and Scotland",
      "England, Wales, Scotland and Northern Ireland"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "England, Wales and Scotland",
    "category": "Geography"
  },
  {
    "id": 38,
    "questionText": "England, Wales, Scotland and Northern Ireland are governed only by the parliament in Westminster.Is this true or false?",
    "answers": ["True", "False"],
    "correctAnswer": "False",
    "category": "Government and Politics"
  },
  {
    "id": 39,
    "questionText": "Which flower is associated with Northern Ireland?",
    "answers": ["Tulips", "Daisy", "Shamrock", "Poppy"],
    "correctAnswer": "Shamrock",
    "category": "Symbols and Monuments"
  },
  {
    "id": 40,
    "questionText": "Which flower is associated with Scotland?",
    "answers": ["Tulips", "Daisy", "Shamrock", "Thistle"],
    "correctAnswer": "Thistle",
    "category": "Symbols and Monuments"
  }
]
